export const chapter = "Chapter - 7: Education and British Rule";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What were the two main systems of education in India when the East India Company began its involvement?",
        optionA: "British System and Indian System",
        optionB: "Hindu System and Muslim System",
        optionC: "Modern System and Traditional System",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the ancient Hindu system of education, who were the teachers in ashrams?",
        optionA: "Government-appointed instructors",
        optionB: "Wealthy landowners",
        optionC: "Sages and scholars",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous ancient universities were part of the Hindu system of education?",
        optionA: "Oxford and Cambridge",
        optionB: "Nalanda and Takshashila",
        optionC: "Harvard and Yale",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the impact of Muslim invasions on the Hindu education system in medieval India?",
        optionA: "It led to the growth of ashrams.",
        optionB: "It had no effect on the education system.",
        optionC: "It caused significant destruction.",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary objective of the British educational system in India during the early 19th century?",
        optionA: "To promote vocational education",
        optionB: "To produce engineers and doctors",
        optionC: "To train clerks for British offices",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Macaulay recommend in his Minute on Indian Education in 1835?",
        optionA: "The use of Sanskrit as the medium of instruction",
        optionB: "The introduction of English as the medium of instruction",
        optionC: "The preservation of traditional Indian education",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were the main objectives of the Christian missionaries in promoting English education in India?",
        optionA: "Spreading Indian culture and heritage",
        optionB: "Converting Indians to Christianity",
        optionC: "Promoting traditional Indian knowledge",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were the limitations of the British education system introduced in India?",
        optionA: "It focused on mass education and rural areas.",
        optionB: "It emphasized scientific and technical education.",
        optionC: "It neglected mass education, especially in rural areas.",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did the introduction of English education lead to in India, according to the text?",
        optionA: "A decline in traditional Indian values",
        optionB: "A stronger emotional bond between different communities",
        optionC: "Increased support for the British colonial rule",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "When did the First War of Independence in India break out, and what was the state of English education at that time?",
        optionA:
          "The war broke out after the widespread adoption of English education.",
        optionB:
          "The war broke out before the introduction of English education.",
        optionC:
          "The war had no connection to the state of English education in India.",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "In the ancient time, the educational system was based on ________. These were built and organized by sages or other scholars.",
        optionA: "Temples",
        optionB: "Ashrams",
        optionC: "Forts",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Hindu system of education included oral teaching, and students studied different subjects, with religious texts forming an important part of the syllabus. The sage was the only ______ (teacher) in these ashrams.",
        optionA: "Mentor",
        optionB: "Guru",
        optionC: "Instructor",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Hindu education system had renowned universities like ______ and Takshashila.",
        optionA: "Oxford",
        optionB: "Nalanda",
        optionC: "Harvard",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Muslim System of Education included maktabs for basic education and ______ for higher education.",
        optionA: "Temples",
        optionB: "Madrasas",
        optionC: "Churches",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Under the Muslim system, the emphasis was on Arabic, Persian, and Islamic knowledge, and students often practiced ______ learning.",
        optionA: "Rote",
        optionB: "Experimental",
        optionC: "Creative",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In both the Hindu and Muslim systems, modern knowledge was mostly ______.",
        optionA: "Emphasized",
        optionB: "Excluded",
        optionC: "Celebrated",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British officials like William Jones and Colebrook thought that the ancient Indian knowledge was rich and should comprise the syllabus in the new educational system, with the introduction of ______ on a limited scale.",
        optionA: "Mathematics",
        optionB: "Science",
        optionC: "Logic",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Lord Wellesley set up the Fort William College in 1800 to train company civil servants in Indian languages and customs. These efforts were his ______ initiative.",
        optionA: "Personal",
        optionB: "Government",
        optionC: "Missionary",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Charter Act of 1813 provided an annual grant of one lakh rupees for introducing English education in India, and it led to the Oriental-Occidental Controversy about the choice of ______ as the medium of instruction.",
        optionA: "Vernacular languages",
        optionB: "Arabic",
        optionC: "English",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Sir Charles Wood's Despatch of 1854, also known as Wood's Despatch, emphasized the diffusion of the improved arts, services, philosophy, and literature of Europe, promoting ______ knowledge.",
        optionA: "European",
        optionB: "Indian",
        optionC: "African",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Plants that grow in forests or jungles are called jungle plants.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced English education to promote the study of traditional Indian knowledge.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The ancient Hindu education system was based on ashrams organized by scholars.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Hindu system of education included oral teaching and the study of different subjects.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Muslim System of Education emphasized modern knowledge and excluded Arabic and Islamic subjects.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Sir Charles Wood's Despatch of 1854 emphasized the diffusion of European knowledge in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced English education in India to produce engineers and doctors.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Lord Wellesley set up the Fort William College in 1800 to train company civil servants in Indian languages and customs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Charter Act of 1813 provided a substantial annual grant to promote English education in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The introduction of English education in India led to the decline of traditional Indian values.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
